HILDA S. IBRIGA

Address: 3378 Peppermill Dr, Apt 1A, West Lafayette, IN, 47906

• Phone: (917) 330-4180 • Email: Hibriga@purdue.edu • Webpage: https://hilda-ibriga.me

Objective: I am a Ph.D. student in Statistics with four years of research experience centered around developing machine learning models and tensor data analysis. I also have three years of statistical consulting work experience. Find my complete research, work, projects and leadership profile on my personal website.

SKILLS

- Statistics: Statistics Consulting, Design of Experiments, GLM, Mixed Effect Models, Machine Learning models, Tensor data analysis, Bayesian analysis, MCMC methods.
- **Programming**: experienced in R, Python, SAS, MATLAB, SQL, C++.
- Language: English, French(native fluency)

EDUCATION

Purdue University, Department of Statistics, West Lafayette, IN

Expected 08/2021

- Ph.D. candidate in Statistics
- Research Areas: Tensor-Variate Analysis, Machine Learning, Non-Convex Optimization
- Advisors: Dr. Wei Sun, and Dr. Bruce Craig

University of Arkansas, Department of Mathematics, Fayetteville, AR

05/2014

- M.S. in Mathematics GPA: 3.94/4.00
- Recipient of Lawrence Jesser Toll Award (2014)

Westminster College, Department of Mathematics, Fulton, MO

05/2011

- B.A. in Mathematics and Economics (Double major) GPA: 4.00/4.00
- Graduated With Highest Distinction

WORK EXPERIENCES

The Data Mine Purdue, West Lafayette, IN: Head Teaching Assistant

08/2019 - present

- Supervised a group of 12 TAs and organized and ran TA training meetings.
- Contributed in co-writing and reviewing all R, Python and SQL course projects.
- Held office hours and led projects grading meetings.
- Contributor and editor of the DataMine example book.

ASANA, San Francisco, CA: Data Science Intern

05/2018 - 08/2018

- Conducted comparative research on two competing model agnostic machine learning interpretability methods Lime and Anchor.
- Integrated Lime into the existing machine learning model for predicting account churn which allowed to:
 - Identify features which explain high churning probability for a given account
 - facilitate understanding and actionability for the business team
- Co-wrote documentation for the implementation and integration of Lime into the account churning model

Purdue Consulting Services, West Lafeyette, IN: Statistics Consultant

08/2015 - 12/2018

- Worked on 50+ consulting projects in Engineering, Social Sciences and Natural Sciences fields.
- Assisted clients at each of the fundamental statistical modeling steps:
 - Defining scope of project, design of experiment,
 - Data quality control, data analysis and visualization using R, SAS, MATLAB or SQL
 - Results interpretation and writing for journal publication, technical report and grant proposal.
- Projects include social network analysis, sample size calculation for complex experimental designs, analysis of large time series data, metrics engineering.
- Co-authored the free manual titled "Introduction to the Statistical Software R", to provide a quick introduction to R for the use of faculty and students at Purdue University.

Advertisement Clustering via Coupled Tensor Completions with Side Information

- Developed an algorithm (COSTCO) which performs joint spectral decomposition for high dimensional data array and a matrix coupled along one mode using alternating minimization method.
- Showed that method is robust to high percentage of missing data, sparsity and noise level in data through extensive simulation and application on online advertisement data.
- Demonstrated that method can be combined to clustering algorithm to reveal new and interesting ad clusters key for to plan better ad strategies.
- Currently building R package for COSTCO.

Engineering Metrics for Engineers Teamwork Ratings Quality Assessment

- Led a group of three engineers to developed metrics and statistical methods for accessing the quality of ratings data generated by the CATME system.
- Built prototype tools for automating data cleaning and analysis in R and SAS.
- Created instruction manuals and Run live demo of new tools to help CATME system users run analyses independently.
- New tools are to be integrated into the CATME system which is currently deployed to more than 1 million users from 80 countries.

Locating and Quantifying the Effect of QTL using EM Algorithm and Bayesian Lasso Method

- Implemented an EM algorithm in R which sequentially locates and estimates the magnitude of the eects of 176 markers on blood pressure in mice.
- Performed a permutation test to compute the critical value for the test statistics.
- Used a hierarchical model approach with a non-informative prior on the tuning parameter to implement Bayesian Lasso in R which allowed for simultaneously testing the location and effect of all markers at once.
- Used a Gibb sampler to sample from the full conditional posterior of 341 parameters and hyper-parameters.

Disease Status Prediction and Growth Trend of Aortic Aneurysms

- Used high frequency ultrasound aneurysm data to develop prediction models of both aneurysm formation and growth trend.
- Used a quadratic discriminant analysis and logistic regression to build two statistical models to predict disease status.
- Validated model performance through leave one out cross validation prediction accuracy, ROC curve, specificity and sensitivity analysis.

RESEARCH AND PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Hilda S Ibriga, Will Wei Sun, and Bruce Craig. Inference and uncertainty quantification for covariate-assisted sparse tensor completion. *Manuscript*, 2021
- 2. Hilda S Ibriga and Will Wei Sun. Covariate-assisted sparse tensor completion and applications to advertisement clustering. *Submitted*, 2021 arXiv: 2103.06428
- 3. Rebecca Rivera, McKenna Deckard, Dennis Savaiano, Krystal Lynch, Melissa Maulding, Hilda Ibriga, and Heather Eicher-Miller. Reliability of the indiana supplemental nutrition assistance program-education (snap-ed) program evaluation survey (p04-074-19). Current Developments in Nutrition, 3, 2019
- Zachary A. Weber, Palakpreet Kaur, Amrita Hundal, Hilda. Ibriga, and Ashay D. Bhatwadekar. Effect of the pharmacist-managed cardiovascular risk reduction services on diabetic retinopathy outcome measures. Pharmacy Practice, 17, 2019
- 5. D. M. Ferguson, M. W. Ohland, C. Lally, H. Ibriga, and Y. Cao. Evaluating the effect of different teamwork training interventions on the quality of peer evaluations. In 2018 IEEE Frontiers in Education Conference (FIE), pages 1–5, 2018
- Amelia R. Adelsperger, Evan H. Phillips, Hilda S. Ibriga, Bruce A. Craig, Linden A. Green, Michael P. Murphy, and Craig J. Goergen. Development and growth trends in angiotensin ii-induced murine dissecting abdominal aortic aneurysms. *Physiological Reports*, 6, 2018
- 7. Daniel M. Ferguson, Chad Lally, Hilda Ibriga, Olivia Murch, and Matthew W. Ohland. Using frame-of-reference training to improve the dispersion of peer ratings in teams. volume 2016-November, 2016

AWARDS

- 2020 Recipient Purdue University Graduate School Ross Fellowship.
- 2014 Winner of the University of Arkansas Lawrence Jesser Toll Award for academic exellence.
- 2012 Recipient of the John C Massie Scholarship
- 2011 Winner of Westminster College Academic Dean of Student Research and Presentation Award for Math thesis research.
- 2010- Inducted into Pi Mu Epsilon Mathematics Honor Society.
- 2007 Awarded the Davis United World College scholarship.

LEARDERSHIP

Statistics in the Community (STATCOM), Purdue University, - Associate Director 08/2016 - 05/2018

- Coordinated projects and supervised teams of graduate and undergraduate students working on pro-bono statistics consulting projects for non-profit organizations.
- Worked with West Lafayette City Council leaders on how to evaluate city development strategy using a data driven approach.
- Delivered project report presentations on-site to organizations.
- Helped run the Statistics booth during Purdue Spring Fest, sharing the joys of statistics by demonstrating simple statistics to children.

Arkansas Women in Mathematics, - Treasurer

08/2012 - 05/2013

- Helped organize club annual invited speaker event.
- Organized club's budget and bookkeeping.
- Gave talks and presentation on majoring in Mathematics to local high schools.

Pi Mu Alpha Mathematics Honor Society, Westminster College, - President

01/2009 - 01/2010

- Planned and organized activities for the undergraduate math club.
- Gave talks and tours during mathematics prospective student visits.
- Selected as mentor for the class 2014 freshmen mathematics seminar.